[Music]
hi guys and welcome back to my kitchen
now one of my favorite things to make
are cupcakes so on this week's video
tutorial what I thought I'd do is show
you some of my favorite piping tips um
and also show you the styles that they
make um and the techniques I use to pipe
the buttercream onto the cupcakes let's
get started okay so I've got my cupcakes
I've got the piping tips I'm going to
show you I've got my um icing bags a
spatula and my buttercream okay so the
first buttercream swell that I'm going
to show you is using this piping tip
which is the Wilton 1M and as you can
see it's got a star shape at the top now
I think this one creates the most
popular of the buttercream SRS and this
is your classic ice cream
SWR okay so what I'm going to do is just
take um this is just a clear Piping Bag
and I'm just going to trim
front of the piping bag off and you just
want to make sure that that's kind of in
there and you can pull it tight without
it coming off we're going to fill
that with
buttercream now I'll put a link below to
the buttercream recipe that I've used
here and I've just colored this with a
rose
pink okay so once you've put your
buttercream into your Piping Bag what
you want to do is just push the
buttercream down so that it starts
coming out at the end is just twist the
end of the bag just to keep it closed
and then with your thumb and your first
finger just keep it in there now this is
the hand that's going to um add the
pressure so this is going to push the
buttercream out and your other hand is
just for guiding or if you just wanted
to pipe with one hand you could use the
other one just to hold the cupcake
steady okay so what we're going to do is
just start with the icing tip here and
I'm just going to start it here on the
Cupcake so applying slight pressure to
the end of the Piping Bag bag we're just
going to bring it around for one
rotation just hugging the side of the
cupcake case now when we reach the join
there we just want to bring the nozzle
in slightly so it's half covering the
buttercream that's already there and
half covering the cupcake again do that
again for another rotation and then
bring it into the middle and pull up and
that's going to give
you your ice cream star well
okay so the next tip that I'm actually
going to show you is this one now it
doesn't have any numbers on it um and it
tends to come in a set um of
professional piping tips which is
available from cake decorating shops um
online
retailers um supermarkets and places
like that now there are similar ones um
in branded ones as well so just have a
lookout for this kind of tip so what
we've got is a flat star on the top now
what this one is going to do is is going
to create really pretty Ruffles okay so
here we have our cupcake and we're going
to use exactly the same technique that
we used for the previous one so again
we're just going to start from one side
and applying pressure with the right
hand I'm just going to pull this round
hugging the side of the cupake case and
then again bring it in so we're half on
the buttercream and half on the Cupcake
I'm going to do three Swirls and then
pull up from the center and there we
have this
really pretty um ruffle SWR and as you
can see it's just got a very different
um kind of effect to the previous
one okay so this is the next piping tip
that we're going to use and what I'm
going to do is show you how to make the
rose cupcake um now this is the Wilton
2D piping tip as you can see all of the
points actually folded over um and meat
in the middle and that's what's going to
give us this really pretty rose effect
okay so with this one what we're going
to do is it's going to be slightly
different and it's going to be in
Reverse so we're going to place the
piping tip in the center of the cupcake
and what we want to do is go around each
of the layers so as we do a rotation we
want to keep going around so we're just
hugging the side of the buttercream
that's already been on there until we
get to the outer layout squeeze gently
to get a bit of the buttercream then
wrap it
around and keep following the previous
layer around
until you come to the
outside of the cupcake case now when
you've got nowhere to go you just want
to pull that buttercream
away and there you have a really pretty
kind of Rose style
cupcake okay so for the last cupcake tip
that I really enjoy using is this one
and this is just an open um Circle tip
now this is going to create um a swirl
like the others but it's just going to
be smooth um and simple and just really
pretty okay so here we have um just the
round tip in there with the buttercream
now be aware that this um piping tip
does use slightly more buttercream than
the others so we're just going to start
on one of the edges of the cupcake bring
it round and you want to hug the
outside of the cupcake case now when you
get to that butter cream you just want
to pull it in and just SL go through
rotations and then pull
up and that's just going to bring it
around into this really pretty butter
cream
swirl now as you can see all these cup
plates are completely different and
these are probably my most used cupcake
tips and the ones I prefer using I
really hope you've enjoyed this video
tutorial if you have then please give it
a thumbs up and if you'd like to see
more video tutorials then please click
subscribe